

Adytia Putra Pradana Data Analyst

Phone : 082121210695

Email : adytiapp@gmail.com

Linked In : www.linkedin.com/in/adytiapp

Hello! My name is Adytia. I am a Data Analyst. Also a viable communicator with extensive experience in data and marketing. With project ranging from customer behavior analysis, customer retention (cohort), customer relationship management, customer segmentation, SKU portfolio, data automation and many more.

I am really passionate in data analytics because I want to solve major problem in Indonesia using data. As an engineering graduate, I have affinity to work with number. Data analytics successfully combines aspects of work that I enjoy such as computation, communication, and visualization.

EXPERIENCE

06/2022 - 05/2023

Marketing Data Analyst

Ula

Assisted marketing team & commercial division as a whole to provide data analysis and insight. Created data automation, data pipeline, and analytics report in dashboard. Created project initiative to help solve marketing team problems Coordinated with other data related position outside marketing to align objectives.

- Increased net margin % to 150% of its previous value by developing SKU portfolio matrix to select best SKU's in terms of net margin and NMV
- Improved Facebook Ads data automation to ad-set level from facebook ads manager/Facebook graph API (increase 200% efficiency)
- Implemented **RFM analysis** to better segment customer. Used higher level customer segment to help performance marketing finding lookalike customer to acquire (3% quarterly increase in champion customers)
- Implemented Customer Lifetime Value for assessing the best paid acquisition channel (roughly >100% ROI on major partners)

11/2022 - Present

Team Lead Data Analytics Mini Course

RevoU

Helped newcomers in Data Analytics and gave them new perspective about Data Analytics prospect in Indonesia. Assessed mini course student progress and gave a detailed review. Helped student by providing guidance in terms of technical & mental aspect. Spoke regularly in select webinar, mainly in topics of job searching, career switching, data analytics including data analytics foundation and tools. Conducted Q&A daily to help student work on their study.

- Increased full program student acquisition by high margin (>10%)
- Regularly teach about 1000 students in each batch (biweekly)

01/2022 - 05/2022

Lead Marketing and Visual Graphics

PT Nur Straits Engineering

Managed marketing team and implementing both traditional marketing and digital marketing activities. Communicated insight and recommendation to the upper management.

- Gained a respectable number of Instagram followers in short amount of time (currently 150+ followers)
- Supervised the development for entire website from the ground up (backend & frontend) for 2 months

08/2020 - 01/2022

Tender Engineer & Graphic Designer

PT Nur Straits Engineering

Tender winning percentage >60%. Which is very high among competitors. Developed tender databases such as expert data, project data, company legal data to increase productivity and winning rate. Designed visual graphics for company look and feel such as company presentation, company attributes, company reports.

Biggest projects won:

- Detailed Engineering Design for Tjilik Riwut Palangkaraya and HAS Hanandjoeddin Airport Overlay
- Jasa Marga Bridges Study Consultancy Services (TA 2020)

02/2018 - 04/2020

Proposal & Marketing Staff

PT Indra Karya (Persero)

Developed spreadsheet based tender database system for upcoming tender. - increased productivity rate by approximately 30%. Communicating which tender has the highest probability of winning and influence stakeholder to make decisions.

Biggest projects won:

• Supervision of the Tanjung Emas Branch Port Pond Dredging Work

EDUCATION

2013-2017 Geological Engineering

Padjadjaran University - Bachelor Degree

GPA: 3.68/4.00

Member of Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa Himpunan Mahasiswa Geologi Universitas Padjadjaran

in Human Resource and Organization Development.

CERTIFICATES

03/2022 - Lifetime RevoU Full Stack Data Analytics

11/2021 - 11/2023 ETS TOEFL - Score 617

SKILLS

Tools

Google Sheets/Excel Intermediate Intermediate Tableau SQL Intermediate Google Apps Script Intermediate Redash Intermediate Appsflyer Intermediate Looker/Google Data Studio Intermediate Figma Intermediate Python Intermediate Adobe Illustrator Intermediate

LANGUAGES

English Fluent Indonesian Native